Heat
[Music]
up
Heat. Hey, Heat.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome Welcome back to the Ask
Abijit show. Today we are doing episode
270. That's quite a number, isn't it? Uh
I hope everyone is doing great. Let me
see who all is there on the live stream
with me with us over here. I can see
Mujio Africanos Ulas Swami Jin anonymous
scientist. Draj Kamat says good morning.
Well, good morning to you. Uh Anadi says
good evening. Yash Got Shri Ramchandra
Dungar Singh Chawan Shesh Chrian Chuma
N2
Ritik Bad Mr. Jam Radhi Radi Abhishek
Shivastav Geopolitical Dway from Indor
Sumit Agarwal
uh Pranav Anadi Daksh Vikash PJ Namaste
Sena
Sep Raj Krishna Giri good evening Aush
Sin Singh Aush Singh Prane Paul from
Kolkata Shiva Sai and who else do we
have Aman Jot Singh has put in a super
chat well okay atman mosha Rahul Dunak
Kanesh Kanesh Koshik
uh Manoj Zawar Anand Chandak Sandy 97
Adish Rajput Vikash again Chitan Aradhya
Abhishek Tanesh Pand the civilizational
warrior feminist slayer hunter duv durya
truthful penguin Abhishek Shivastav
Sumit Agarwal Bageshwar Army Makleven
Vikas PJ Rajor Shik Good evening Tanmay
Tanesh Pandy Ad swapil das tanoi Ankita
Bushan and so many other people. So
thank you so much all of you for being
on the live chat. Somi Jane is from
Jaipur, Mloin from Hawaii, Anumita Roy,
Priyanka Javalia and everybody else
Vimla. So yeah, so uh I'm going to take
questions from that that you have asked
in the comments as I'm as I hope
everybody's aware and at the end if
there is some time we're going to I'll
take a few questions maybe from the live
chat.
What questions are we covering today?
There's a whole lot of questions. Here
are some of the questions. We're going
to talk about Air India, the Air India
crash, uh Russia. We're going to talk
about Tibet. We're going to talk about
Trump and the Epstein files.
uh the Fiser bribery probe. Uh Elon Musk
and his new party. We're going to uh
talk about uh we're going to talk about
uh these things here, citizenship,
foreign policy, domestic policy, best
countries. We're going to talk about
Greece, Cyprus, Armenia. We're going to
talk about bricks. We're going to talk
about Argentina, Brazil, uh, China, BBC,
Shikasina, nuclear weapons, B2 bombers,
Thailand, Chingis Khan, agriculture to
hunting, Arian invasion, Einstein,
whether he's overhyped or not, cast and
so many other things. That's some of the
things we're going to talk about. I know
that it's just a few questions, maybe
2022 questions. I know a lot of people
have asked questions. U I won't be able
to take all of them. The the objective,
please remember, of this show is to take
the best possible questions and the
objective is to give the best possible
most important information to as many
people as possible through this show. So
don't be unhappy or discouraged if your
question hasn't been taken. The
objective is to
um discuss whatever is most relevant and
important in the world right now. So
let's get going with the questions.
We're going to talk about this one
first.
Nimish Gupta says the preliminary crash
report of Air India Ahmedabad's crash
came out recently citing the mysterious
turn off of fuel switches to the engines
moments after takeoff even though
neither of the pilots two pilots did it.
How could this happen? What are my
views?
So there are it's it's the mystery is
actually deepening rather than the
mystery being resolved. So first of all
this report has come out. um uh the
government of India has put out this
report. It's it's uh from uh a
government agency that the report has
come out and the government agency what
is what is it called? I'm not sure. It's
it's one of the government agencies and
they put out the report. It's been but
the funny thing the strange thing the
curious thing is that the report seems
to have been leaked
before it was uh put out in the public
domain for for the Indian public.
So about a day before the report
officially was published or or disclosed
to the public, it was leaked to the Wall
Street Journal, an American publication.
That is very strange. The question is
who leaked it? If it's a government
agency that has prepared the report,
then who from within the government
leaked it to the Americans?
This is very serious. It's not a joke.
Is is our country a joke or what? Is it
so easy to leak our sensitive and and
important material to foreign countries
before it is put out in the public
domain for our citizens?
A day before it comes out in front of
our citizens, the Wall Street Journal
has the findings and they put out the
findings, whatever the findings are. And
it's a preliminary report. It's not the
final report. And according to this
report, it looks like u there are this
fuel switches in the aircraft
uh which seem to have been both put to
fuel cutff within 1 second of each
other. So there's one for the left
engine, one for the right engine.
And uh it's it's not possible to simply
just you know by by mistake accidentally
put the switch to the off button or or
to the put the switch to the off
position or cut off position. you to
pull it out then bring it down. Pull it
out and bring it down. And there are
these guardrails on both sides that
prevent uh any accidental touch of those
two uh switches.
So the report says uh now how how do you
how does the report figure out what
happened? How did the investigation
figure out what actually happened?
Right? That's that's that's an important
question that we we have to ask
ourselves. So there are multiple things
that go that that are used to
investigate what happened. First of all,
you have the actual crashed aircraft
whatever is left of it. Uh you can um
you know find the cockpit. It may be
scattered and strewn strewn around but
the switches generally stay in the
position that they were left in at the
end and so on. That's one thing. Then
you have the aircraft uh the cockpit
voice recorder and then there's the
cockpit data recorder. And there are two
of these. One is in the two of these are
in the back side of the aircraft, one,
two are in the front and uh these were
recovered.
So, so the voice recorder apparently uh
there is a recording of one pilot asking
the other. There were two pilots. One is
the senior pilot, one is the junior one.
There's one pilot asking the other why
did you cut off the fuel? Essentially,
paraphrasing. Okay, I'm paraphrasing
here. Why did you cut off the fuel? And
the other guy says I did not. And that's
about it. There was not enough time to
have a further discussion and then the
aircraft crashes. That's what it says.
Okay, that's what the report, the
preliminary report says. And it says
that those fuel switches were in the
cutff position, which means that
somebody manually
set the two fuel switches to the cutff
position, which means the the engines
were the the the flow of fuel to the
engines was stopped. That's what the
report says. And apparently the the
switches were found in the cutff
position or something. U but it also
says no they were not found in the cut
off position because then apparently the
switches were then reset to the on
position. So the fuel was again
restarted. The flow of fuel was again
restarted to the engines. That's kind of
what the report says.
So if we go by what the report says, the
aircraft takes off. It took off. Then
one of the two pilots apparently
as per the report cut off the fuel to
both the engines and then there was a
there was an interaction. One pilot
asked the other why why did you do that
and this guy the other guy says I did
not do it and then the report says that
the f the switches were again reset to
the on position but by the time it was
too late to save the aircraft
because this all happened in a matter of
seconds.
That's what this report, this
preliminary report says. Now the first
question is
why was this report leaked and who
leaked it? Is this a joke? Is our
country a joke that that these reports
are to be leaked to foreign countries?
Right? That's number one. Secondly,
secondly, if there is this recording,
okay, of a pilot saying to the other, of
one pilot asking asking the other pilot,
why did you set the fuel switches to the
to the cutff position?
Why isn't it being released to the
public? If you go to YouTube, there are
plenty of videos of uh is cockpit voice
recordings that happened prior to
crashes,
aircraft crashes.
So this is a very very important issue
for the for for for for India
and for for the sake of full
transparency
if such a recording exists
then it should be released to the public
to the to the to the public. It should
be released by the government and and
the actual authentic recording should be
released. Today it's very easy to
fabricate recordings.
It's very Easy.
Okay, looks like we are back.
Surprising this doesn't happen usually,
right? But uh looks like the there was
an issue with the internet. Uh anyhow,
my point is that look, today it's very
easy to use AI to to create fake
recordings to create fake uh yeah
recordings of people. You can clone
someone's voice easily and you can
fabricate any kind of recording. You can
even clone someone's face and create a
video in which somebody appears to be
saying something but it's an AI
generated video. Similarly, you can
create AI generated recordings. My point
is that for the sake of full public
accountability and transparency, if the
government says that this happened, they
should release the recording, the
authentic recording to the public.
Just saying that this happened is not
going to cut it. I I I personally will
not believe it. Okay. This has to be
released to the public and it has to be
the authentic recording.
Then the question also arises like is it
possible for these these fuel switches
to to
somehow automatically be shut down to to
be set to the off position? Is it
possible? Is it possible that there
could be some software flaw that could a
flaw that could cause the uh the system
to interpret the switch as being being
uh as been having um as having been turn
set to the off position to to the cut
off position. There are lots of
questions. I think this preliminary
report whatever it is it raises more
questions than it gives answers.
And obviously there are very big issues
at stake over here. there's the credib
there's the reputation and credibility
of Air India that's at stake and even
bigger than that there's a bigger
company whose reputation is at stake
which is Boeing and it has had issues
uh so I think I am I am I'm I would say
that it's too early to make any judgment
I think we should wait and watch I think
it's it's too early to jump to
conclusions
needs to handle this very carefully
first of all whoever lead the report
needs to be named and shamed and and
sacked. Not suspended, sacked and and
thrown into jail.
This happens very just too often
these leaks from the government of India
from within the government of India.
This happens too often there all kinds
of issues. So my my views are that this
raises more questions than answers. I am
not convinced yet.
I mean these sort of things have
unfortunately happened in the past.
German wings comes to mind
2015 then there was a Chinese aircraft
that comes to mind. So these were cases
in which the pilots themselves crashed
the aircraft. Okay. There have been some
cases very unfortunate cases like these.
Is this one of those cases? I am not
convinced yet.
First of all, the question is who did
the investigation?
Am I audible? I think I'm audible now.
Uh just please confirm on the live chat
if if uh I am audible. There seems to be
weird stuff going on today.
Uh nothing yet. People are saying I'm
not audible. Hello. Hello. Testing.
Yes, I'm audible. Perfect. Okay, so this
seems to be rather weird. First of all,
the image goes away, then the audio goes
away, whatever it is. Okay, we are back.
I have fixed the issue. Uh,
so I am not convinced yet and I think
that the government needs to look into
this very very seriously. Um
and uh whatever evidence is there, it
needs to be transparently made available
to the people of India completely fully.
And uh the question also is whether this
was decoded the data was extracted at
home in India in Delhi or wherever in
India or was it sent outside of India in
which case there is you know there is a
full possibility of of something being
manipulated.
So uh I am not sure what is VK videos. I
don't know whatever it is. Okay. So that
is the the first uh question. So my
answer is that my my views are that I am
not convinced yet. I think we need to
it's too early for us to jump to
conclusions. We need to wait and watch.
The government needs to set its house in
order. Whoever leaked these things to
the Americans needs to be caught and and
made an example of. And secondly,
whatever is actually the output of the
outcome of this needs to be completely
transparently put in in front of the
public of India. Until that happens, um
I'm going to wait and watch. I'm not
going to uh rush to any conclusions.
Okay.
Right. Let's take question number two. I
hope I am still audible. Yeah. Okay.
What's the second question? Okay. This
is by Ewan Singh. Why has there been no
large retaliation from Russia after the
significant escalation by Ukraine? Has
Putin gone soft?
Has Putin gone soft? So last month, I
think around the around the 1st of June,
uh Ukraine launched these long range
strikes into Russia, right? Operation
spider web in which um they they struck
at Russian air bases thousands of
kilometers within Russia um through a
variety of means. We'll not go into
that. and uh more than 10 Russian
aircraft were destroyed and maybe more
than 20 were hit and damaged. The
Ukrainians claimed that more than 40
were hit but obviously that is an ex
exaggeration. I think American
intelligence itself has assessed that
about 10 were dam were destroyed and
total 20 were hit 20 2122 something like
that that number. So that was
significant right and there the there
was the Kirch bridge in in uh the
Crimean bridge that was hit and so on.
So the Ukrainians have gone after the
Russians. The question is has Putin gone
soft? Has been has there been no real
large retaliation from Russia after all
these things? Well, if you watched my
episode of Geost Strategy yesterday, you
will know that Russia has recently like
a couple of days ago launched its
largest aerial assault assault on
Ukraine. It fired more than 700 missiles
and drones in a single attack. And that
too, this attack was launched just a few
I mean just a few minutes essentially
after Putin spoke with Trump on the
phone.
So Putin said I'm going to escalate
despite this diplomatic engagement that
I'm having with the US. So that's a
massive retaliation, right? And if you
look at the statistics for the month of
June, Russia launched more than 5,600
drones and missiles at Ukraine in the
month of June itself. I'm not even
talking about July. So there's no going
soft. Absolutely not.
You need to keep an eye on what's what's
actually happening. Right. So Russia has
not gone soft. Russia is actually
escalating and it obviously wants to use
this for uh for leverage during uh
diplomatic interactions and
negotiations. The better your position
is on the battlefield, the more leverage
you have on the diplomatic negotiating
table. That is how it goes, right?
Diplomacy doesn't mean that you just go
and talk and say peace peace peace. No,
you first achieve things on the
battlefield. You achieve a superior
position that you can use as leverage on
the diplomatic table. Diplomacy is an
extension of war. War is an extension of
diplomacy. That's how it goes. The
objective is to achieve your political
uh and and geopolitical goals. So uh
that's the situation currently.
Okay. Pray Paul and uh SS etc. Say the
question is about uh so prol says with
the US department of justice quietly
closing fizer's bribery probe and Trump
dodging the Epstein questions isn't it
clear that even US presidents have
limits and some powers lie five be lie
far beyond the white house was it all
knows all of this just noise to win
elections and the other question is with
Trump refusing to release the Epstein
files speculation seems to be going
around that Mossad has a lot of leverage
on the CI on the USA and other big folks
in the deep state. What are my views on
this? Okay,
let's this Mossad angle is all
speculation. It may have some there may
be some truth to it. Okay, it's
possible. But in the absence of any sort
of evidence that points in the
direction, we not going to discuss that
here. Otherwise we we are just some
other bunch of idiots doing conspiracy
theory talk without any evidence. We're
going to discuss things by based on
whatever facts are out there available
in the public domain. Okay.
So what are the facts that are out there
in the public domain? First of all, uh
Trump has essentially you could say
claimed that there there are no Epstein
files. Well, Trump hasn't said it
himself. It is uh uh the FBI that that
is saying it, right? Uh what's his name?
Kasha Patel. Cash Patel. He's the boss
of the the head of the FBI and he's been
going around on various podcasts saying
that there there are no Epstein files.
It simply doesn't exist. It's a myth. A
few months ago, his boss Pam Bondai was
saying that I'm going to release the
Epstein files im imminently. Never
happened. In a few months, the the the
Epstein files seem to have evaporated
into thin air. And now the stand
official stand of the Trump
administration is that these so-called
Epstein files simply don't exist.
So, well,
and and in the run-up to the elections,
it was all I'm going to release
everything. I'm going to release the JFK
JFK, the truth about the JFK
assassination. I'm going to release the
Epstein files. I'm going to release
everything. Right. Trump was I remember
asked in some some interaction some
interview or some podcast that uh that
will you be willing to release the
Epstein files and he had kind of tried
to dodge the question but grudgingly
said yes to said something like yes but
now the stand is that these Epstein
files don't exist and Elon Musk has in
the past
rather recently made the allegation that
Trump himself figures on the in the
Epstein files okay that's the that's an
allegation Elon Musk did he tweeted that
on his platform X and then after a few
days he deleted the the tweet and then
he expressed regret that I shouldn't I I
crossed the line I shouldn't have said
that
but if you look at old old videos that
exist you can see Trump and Epstein
together in during a party both dancing
together and Trump pointing out various
things to Epstein and both laughing etc.
So there's there was a connection for
sure for for sure. I'm not sure what
kind of connection was there
but it was there and well Elon Musk went
went ahead and said that Trump figures
on the Epstein files. He's one of those
Epstein I don't know possibly clients I
don't know allegedly right. Uh so that
has been pushed aside swept under the
carpet the Epstein thing. Uh then the
Fiser bribery probe that also has been
has been quietly closed that also been
swept under the carpet. Uh so everything
is being swept under the carpet. Who
does it serve? It serves whoever was
benefiting from this during the Biden
administration and that's why people say
it's the deep state. And I myself have
said this before. I said this before the
election happened. I said this last year
if Trump I I had said at the time that
there was a very little low chance that
Trump would win. I was of the opinion
that Trump would not win and I also said
that if Trump does win it will mean that
he has kissed the ring.
Now kissing the ring is is a metaphor.
It's it's it's something that you see in
mafia movies. The Godfather
the Godfather is this shadowy figure who
has the ring. And to to prove to signal
your allegiance to him, you got to go
and kiss his ring that he wears on his
on his well fingers.
Right? So I said I had said this last
year that Trump will win the presidency
only if he kisses the ring of the deep
state and becomes
becomes what? Becomes uh an agent of the
deep state. That's the only condition
under which he wins otherwise there's no
chance. So well he did win and initially
he was like I'm going to go after the
deep state. I have this department of
government efficiency. I'm going to cut
the fat, trim the fat, get rid of the
all the bureaucrats and that's the deep
state. He was trying to mislead the
public and claim that by cutting by by
by firing by sacking a lot of
bureaucrats and and reducing the number
of bureaucrats. I'm going after the deep
state because the bureaucrats are the
unelected unelected uh government
officials who are the deep state. That's
not the deep state, my dear friend.
That's not the deep state. So what's the
deep state? That's the question. Well,
I've answered this many times in the
past. Let me answer it again. If it does
exist, it's going to be an extra
constitutional, extra democratic, extra
electoral uh power center
that remains in power. No matter who
comes to power as the president, no
matter who wins, which party wins what
election, doesn't matter. There's going
to be a group of people, small group of
people who are tremendously wealthy but
completely unknown or at least not known
and and they they control
essentially the whole country and by
extension much of the world. That's the
deep state if it does exist. I'm not
saying it exists, but if it does exist,
I mean in most countries you have extra
electoral extra democratic power
centers, old power centers that persist.
So that's the deep state and you know
and and obviously lots of politicians
are invested in in Fizer. They are in
the pockets of Fiser allegedly
and apparently lots of politicians are
uh allegedly they figure in the Epstein
files. Now the question again is what is
the Epstein files? So Epstein is this
guy who allegedly committed suicide.
Nobody believes that right? a very very
well-connected guy and he had this
island
and there are flight logs about which
which record which exist which are out
there in the public domain which record
who are the people who who visited this
island and very powerful very prominent
presidents and and politicians a bunch
of them are are frequent visitors
regular visitors repeat visitors to
Epstein island on which all kinds of
horrific things are said to have
happened okay I'll not go into that you
can figure it out for yourself or find
out for yourself. Okay, do that much
homework. Uh and
so
and and the allegation like somebody
there a mention of Mossad here, right?
So the allegation or speculation is that
Epstein was an agent of Mossad of Israel
and he had all these politicians
allegedly that the is the allegation
that he had all the politicians come to
Epstein island where did they did
horrific things which are all filmed
secretly and that gives whoever controls
Epstein all that footage which gives
them tremendous leverage over all these
very powerful politicians American and
other countries and all right. So they
are then those politicians are there
then under the control of whoever
controls whoever owns the footage
they own these politicians for life and
apparently many of them are world
leaders. So which means that whoever
owns the footage allegedly
of all the misdeeds they've done on the
island they own these world leaders and
these prominent politicians which means
they can control the fate of the world.
That is the speculation and allegation
and there is no evidence of this in the
public domain.
None whatsoever. Which is why you can
rightfully call it a conspiracy theory
and which is why I will not discuss that
angle further beyond what the allegation
is. Right? Because there's no way of
knowing. It's it's possible. It's even
it may even be likely. But there's no
evidence. There's not a shred of
evidence of this in the public domain
beyond those flight logs in which you
have former presidents and all visiting
and Elon Musk says even Trump visited.
I've not seen it myself but that's what
he claimed. So that's the deal. That's
the deal.
That is the situation. Uh so is it clear
that US presidents have limits? I have
been saying this for years. Obviously US
presidents are have limits. US
presidents don't really run the country.
They are simply there to divert
attention away from wherever the real
power lies. I've been saying this for
years,
haven't I? I mean, look at Joe Biden. Do
you think he was mentally competent to
run a country like the US? And his
deputy, the vice president, Kamala
Harris, was she mentally competent to
run a country? Neither of them was
mentally competent to run a nation.
But it was being run. It ran itself for
4 years. It did not run and run itself.
somebody ran it. So clearly it doesn't
matter who the president is. Okay. The
the nation the
whoever really runs the country they
will get get their way and sometimes
there's a president who may come along
who may go against the wishes of the
so-called deep state and then 1963
happens. So US presidents have to be
very careful very very very careful.
So well that's about it for this
question. Okay. Uh what else do we have?
Okay, now we have two questions here.
Shri Ramchandraanaha and Prrenipal
again.
So recently the the chief minister of
Arunachal Pradesh Shri Pimakandu said
our border is with Tibet not China. Is
this only a statement or is India
hinting something? And once again the
same question the Arunachal CM said our
border is with Tibet not China. Is this
a major geopolitical signal? Is the
Tibet issue officially back on the
table? Now
we are raising the state the the the the
heat on on China. I mean the chief
minister of Arunachal Pradesh is an
elected official of the government of
India.
Now so this statement that our border is
with Tibet not China has been made at a
very high level in the government of
India at the chief minister level. It
has not come from the central government
yet but it is a clear message to China.
It's a clear message to China and it all
comes in the wake of what has happened
recently. His holiness the Dalai Lama
has made it very clear finally after me
requesting him for many years. He has
made very clear that he will indeed
reincarnate
and he will reincarn and and the process
of of the selection of the next Dalai
Lawa which is the finding of the
reincarnation
is going to happen without external
interference which means that he will
reincarnate outside of Chinese occupied
Tibet or any Chinese occupied territory
which means that the next Dalai Lama
will most likely be based in Dhamala
whenever it happens. So the current
Dalai Lama the 14th Dalai Lama he is
about 90 years old now. So well I hope
he lives to 100 maybe beyond hopefully
but eventually he's going to have to
it's it's I mean it's it's normal right
it's a biological thing you eventually
move on you pass on you give up your
body right and then as per our culture
our civilization our beliefs the soul
reincarnates
so he will reincarnate and then there's
a process of finding this reincarnated
child who has been reborn and the sign
the child will will show certain
characteristics and all and you find
that child and so on. The Chinese want
to do that process within China. They
want to have a Chinese Communist Party
approved Dalai Lama, a CCP Dalai Lama.
That's obviously a fake Dalai Lama.
That's what they want. So India, so the
very fact that his holiness has said
that he's going to be re reborn, he will
reincarnate. He will not attain Nirvana.
will reincarn it and this will happen
outside of Chinese control. It's a huge
statement towards China and now uh the
chief minister of Arunach Pradesh has
made this statement. So it is an it is a
signal that India is sending to China.
We are hardening our position. We will
not be pushed around. China wants to uh
uh ally with Pakistan and use Pakistan
as a geopolitical tool. Fine. Go ahead.
Do whatever you want. But we're going to
push back now. We're going to raise the
stakes on Tibet. We're going to bring
Tibet back to the status of a disputed
territory. So, here is my official
position on Tibet. Tibet is not Chinese
territory. Tibet is illegally,
illegitimately, and brutally occupied by
China. It is under brutal, horrific,
barbaric Chinese occupation.
Tibet is not Chinese territory. Tibet
has never been Chinese. Tibet is a
disputed China ch disputed territory.
Tibet is a disputed territory and India
needs to support the cause of Tibetan
freedom. So eventually Tibet will be
free whenever it happens. That's the
deal. So this is a hardening of India's
stand on China visav on Tibet visav
China because of Chinese provocations
and China deserves it fully and they're
not going to be able to get away with
this uh their attempt to you know claim
that Tibet is Chinese territory and
Manserov has a Chinese name and Kailash
has a Chinese name and and the process
of the reincarnation of the Dalai Lama
will be controlled of the Chinese
Communist Party. none of that. And the
problem is there are many Indians who
are on the Chinese payroll.
Some may not be on the Chinese payroll.
Some may be unwittingly uh ending up
supporting China and helping China's
cause. But some are actually officially
on China. I mean officially means behind
the curtains but actually on Chinese
payroll. There are certain so-called
geopolitical analysts or very active on
on on Twitter who clearly are Chinese
agents. There are certain former uh
political people who have have been at
very high levels in the government of
India in the past who are clearly
Chinese agents. I'm not taking any
names. Okay? And uh there are certain
journalists who help China whenever
whenever China needs help. And there are
some journalists who seem seem to be
idiots. I'm once again not not taking
anybody's name but they also end up
helping China. So yeah that is the
situation but our position vizavi Tibet
is hardening and that's the right way to
go.
Chandani Priya says please explain about
this new political party launched by
Elon Musk. Is it a drama staged by both
Trump and Musk or is the deep state
involved in it? Uh Praep Mitra says
thank you sir. What could be the
possible outcome of Elon Musk's new
political party? Is there any chance for
him to be successful in the US political
field? Multiple questions all rel
related to the same topic. So let's take
these.
Okay. Uh so Elon Musk has launched this
new political party and he had put out a
poll on poll on Twitter in which anybody
could vote including non- US citizens uh
asking whether he should create a
political party and I think the po poll
results said yes even though
non-Americans could vote on it. So it's
not like a proper poll but all right
that's how it goes on Twitter I mean
I've run polls on Twitter in the past
it's now called X whatever in which
obviously non-Indians can vote so it's
not something that's binding or
something you can show as evidence but
whatever so um his so Elon Musk has
created this new political political
party and this is in response to this
this so-called big beautiful bill of
Donald Trump which Elon Musk describes
as as debt slavery and that's something
that resonates with a lot of Americans
debt you know a lot of Americans aren't
really well off I mean the per capita
GDP is very high compared to India but
there's a lot of Americans who have uh
yearly incomes of 30,000 40,000 US you
know which is below average and they
they struggle to to make ends meet they
generally have to you to work two three
jobs just to put food on the table for
their families. And there's all kinds of
problems in America. The US is a
wonderful place to live in if you are
wealthy.
But if you're not wealthy, it's it's
it's could be could be described as
hell.
And if you're a student, my goodness,
you start off your life after your
education with a 100 2003 $100,000 of
debt which you're going to spend the
next 30 years paying paying off. What a
horrific system it is. And medical uh
care is extremely expensive. Dental care
is extremely expensive. Everything is
super expensive in the US. I mean, if
you live in New York City, even even if
you're earning $100,000 a year, it's
barely enough to get by if you are
alone. If you have a spouse and and and
children, well, you got to earn $150,000
plus, I suppose, per per year just to
have a decent okay uh quality of life.
otherwise you're going to be in trouble.
So, so there's a lot of most American
citizens are are saddled with a lot of
debt and Elon Musk has described Trump's
bill big beautiful bill as something
that uh that that uh you know it it
perpetuates debt slavery. So that's
going to resonate with a lot of
Americans, a lot of poor Americans or or
average uh income level Americans for
sure. and then they're okay with this
coming from a billionaire, the the
wealthiest person in the world. So that
is the deal. That's this political party
and he and you know Elon Musk has this
what uh former US president called a
bully pulpit which is this huge
platform. I mean Elon Musk I suppose is
the most followed person on on X on
Twitter and he owns the platform and he
owns this this AI called Grock. Gro four
has come out recently and uh Grock 4
whatever you ask it it's going to be in
line the answer is always going to be in
line with Elon Musk's u ideology and and
uh worldview right so Elon Musk has got
this very powerful platform that he can
leverage to build up his political
movement if he wants to so he has
launched this new political party it's
it's it's in the nent phase right now
it's it's just in beginning phase. Uh
the question is is is this a drama
that's been staged by Trump and Elon
Musk together? Is the deep state
involved in it?
I think there's a 50% probability. I
think not 50% maybe maybe 30% chance
that Trump and Musk are working together
and pretending to be fighting pretending
to have this rift and eventually they
will reconcile at a future date. I think
there's a 30% chance of this happening.
Okay. over the next three years. At some
point in time, they will reconcile and
and join forces. That's also a
possibility. Uh and if Trump is involved
in this, then the deep state is involved
in this because Trump has kissed the
ring. Trust me on this. Trump has kissed
the ring. And even if Trump isn't
involved in this,
Elon Musk has kissed the ring. So
whatever happens, whichever way it goes,
the deep state, if it does exist,
it's involved. Okay? I mean Elon Musk,
he serves the geopolitical agenda of
whoever is in power. Everything he does
serves the geopolitical agenda. Whether
it is Starlink, whether it is Space X,
whether it is Tesla, whether it is
whatever else, he is an integral
component of the overall long-term
geopolitical strategy of the US.
Everything he does, it it helps the US
geopolitically.
Uh so obviously he's going to have deep
state connections whether you know it or
not whether you realize or not. Okay.
Now the question is what could be the
possible outcome of this new political
party? Is there any chance for him to be
successful in the US political field?
First of all please understand if you
aren't if you are a US citizen but you
were born outside the US. If you are
born in a foreign country, you are not
eligible to be the US president unless
you Barack Obama. I mean there have been
allegations that he was born outside of
the US. Trump himself has made these
allegations repeatedly. So I am simply I
am I am not pushing or peddling a
conspiracy theory. I am simply saying
what the current US president has said
on very on a very large number of
occasions. The current president of the
US has said that Barack Obama was most
likely born outside of uh US territory
which should have made him ineligible to
be US president but whatever things
anything goes in the US. Uh now Elon
Musk we know for sure was born outside
the US. He was born in South Africa. He
was born a South African citizen and
then he acquired US citizenship through
a long winding roads I mean pretty
easily compared to Indians but yeah uh
so obviously that means just like Arnold
Schwartzenegger
he can't become US president so then the
question is why is Elon Musk doing all
this I mean isn't he supposed to have a
very clear objective
take humanity to Mars and become king of
Mars so why is he wasting his time
playing these political names. But maybe
there is a good reason for it. I'm not
sure what the reason is. Maybe he has a
good reason for all of this. Uh how
viable is this political party? What's
the possible outcome?
Is he going to be successful in the US
political field? Well, if you want to be
successful in politics, you have to
devote your full attention to politics.
You have to become a full-time
politician.
You can't be a guy who runs the most
successful space launch company, SpaceX,
who runs runs the most successful
electric vehicle company, one of the top
top five, top three, which is Tesla.
You're also running u uh Starlink, which
is the number one satellite
constellation, satellite internet
constellation in the world. You have all
these things you're running, but you
also want to be in politics. You have to
choose one of the two.
or maybe Elon Musk's party could could I
don't know since he can't be president
will they put up a presidential nominee
a candidate who is not Elon Musk. So, I
think it's it's right now pretty
um unclear, but what is clear is that
Elon Musk has the platform and if he
plays the game right, he can he can turn
this into a huge movement simply because
he's the most followed person on Twitter
and he owns Twitter and he owns uh Grock
this AI system which people refer to all
the time. If you look at Twitter, the
Indians, I mean, not just Indians,
people all over the world, they'll keep
factchecking by asking Grock, "Hey,
Grock, is this true?" They don't want to
do do their own research. So, he's
either asking Grock if it's if something
is true or asking perplexity on on
Twitter, but that's how it goes. So,
Elon Musk has this huge advantage. And
in the future, he can even, you know,
push Perplexity down if he wants to
because he owns the platform. So, I
think there's a tremendous amount of
potential there. And if he plays the
game right, he can turn this into a huge
movement. So that's where this could go
in the future.
Okay. Geopolitical Dubai says if bricks,
okay, bricks doesn't have a K, it's B R
I. But I know I get what you mean. If B
bricks does not pose any threat to US
mighty dollar, then why is Trump
frustrated with bricks?
Look, bricks doesn't have a currency of
its own and India has made it very clear
that uh we are not in support of any
bricks currency right so if India
doesn't want a bricks currency then most
likely a bricks currency won't happen
unless China and Russia decide that
India is going to be sidelined and
marginalized or maybe pushed out of
bricks which would then make bricks kind
of irrelevant
right um
so that's the conundrum for for China
Russia obviously
is not anti-India but they are very
strongly dependent on China which is why
they have this issue. uh so a bricks
currency won't happen but what bricks
can do is that see first of all bricks
bricks has its new development bank
which is based in China but whatever so
it's an it's an alternative that n that
nations have an alternative to the world
bank and the international monetary fund
instead of going to the world bank or
the IMF you could go to the new
development bank which is part of which
is owned by bricks uh that's one thing
secondly even if the bricks nations
don't uh even If bricks as as a group
doesn't create its own currency, it can
certainly ensure that the use of the
dollar goes down over time. So bricks
nations can decide that we're going to
trade in our our own currencies. If it's
India and South Africa that are trading,
maybe the trade will be done using the
South African brand and the Indian
rupee. If it's India and the UAE, then
it could be the the rupee dirham thing.
If it's India and Russia, it could be
rupee rubal. If it's China, Russia, it
could be rubal, yuan and so on. So keep
the dollar dollar out that and and
bricks is a big group now it is in terms
of cumulative GDP it's it's larger than
the G7 nations now. So bricks matters
and that's why Trump is is is and the US
they're worried about bricks. So that's
the that's the deal. You know, bricks
can really put a huge dent in the in the
uh in the usage of the US dollar
worldwide and a lot of that will depend
on what India decides to do. So that's
the reason why Trump has this huge
problem with bricks and that's why he's
going after bricks.
Shri Ramachandra Naha says, "What is
India doing to increase its influence in
countries like Argentina and Brazil as
they have lithium and other rare earth
reserves." So if you may be aware, Prime
Minister Modi recently visited both
nations. He was in Brazil. He was in
Argentina. He uh was on a state visit to
Brazil. He was received by uh the
Brazilian leader Mr. Lula. And I think
that's one of the reasons why Xiinping
did not visit visit Brazil for the uh
bricks summit. He chose to stay away. Uh
President Putin did participate in the
bricks summit virtually because of
various issues because there's an arrest
warrant out against him right because of
the Ukraine war. So he did not want to
take the risk of traveling all the way
there. That's I think sensible. But he
did participate Mr. Putin in the brick
summit virtually. Xiinping, President
Shri, he did not travel to Brazil and he
did not even participate virtually.
It's because of the uh state visit of
Prime Minister Modi and Mr. Modi getting
uh so much uh coverage and and the the
focus the attention being on Prime
Minister Modi and Mr. Xinping can't
can't have that, right? He's got to be
number one. So, it doesn't work. So, now
the point is Mr. Modi was in a state
visit to Brazil. Brazil has all these
lots of natural reserves resources and
Mr. Modi also visited Bueno Sai and met
with Mr. Mle the leader of Arantina. So
Mr. Modi himself is is taking the
initiative of establishing and
strengthening not establishing but
strengthening a countryto- country
relations with between India and Brazil,
India and Argentina and this has to be
now taken forward u at various levels in
the in in the respective governments and
this needs to be operationalized and we
need to have uh maybe certain Indian
companies can possibly set up uh
factories or whatever operations mining
operations or whatever in Argentina
possibly if it's if it works in Brazil
pro possibly if it works and you know uh
that could be great for India
but the bigger issue is that we
ourselves have lithium reserves and rare
earth reserves what are we doing to
operationalize those to utilize those
I mean why can't we have Indian
companies set up mining operations
within India there was recently talk of
India finding huge lithium deposits in
Jammu and Kashmir and in other
And we also have significant rare earth
reserves that are known and maybe if we
look for it we we may find even more
rare earth reserves reser reserves in
India. So it is good that we are we are
uh doing whatever doing our best to have
great relations with Brazil and
Argentina and possibly operationalize
some some kind of agreement visav the
rare earths and lithium and all that but
we also have our own reserves and that
is something we should not overlook. we
should set up mining operations within
India. It's very important. These are
very important resources. Uh and
geopolitically very important. So yeah,
that's what needs to be done. But when
it comes to Brazil and Argentina, uh the
government is doing its best to you know
not increase influence but but uh to to
strengthen relations so that we can uh
possibly benefit from the resources they
have to offer.
Okay.
Um, Mclovin and the civilizational
warrior have questions related to the
same topic. As India is selling weapons
to Armenia and probably Greece in the
future, which goes against the interests
of Turkey, does it mean that India is
getting into arms trade and spreading
its geopolitical leverage outside the
subcontinent, giving a tit tit fortat
response to Turkey?
And can India form a military
partnership with Greece, Cyprus, Israel
and Armenia and together work to counter
Turkeykey's influence? J Banani J Banani
J Shivaji. Okay, let's take a look at
the map to understand the the situation.
Give me a second.
Okay, let's put the map on the screen
and let's uh take the text away and
let's imbigon this. Um maybe this is
better. Okay, so the region we're
talking about is the nations around
Turkeykey's periphery. Turkey is a
pretty large nation as you as you can
see here. So we're talking about
Cypress. The northern part of part of
Cyprus was occupied by Turkey in the
1970s and about a third of the island is
under Turkish occupation. Okay. And it
was clearly an act of aggression. U then
you have Greece which Turkey has this
historical enemy with because Turkey has
taken Greek territory. The whole of
Turkey whether it is th whether it's
Anatolia was originally Greek territory.
It was usurped by the Turks by force,
right? And all these cities in in Turkey
used to be Greek cities. And obviously
some of them would have been founded by
the Turks, but these are very old
cities, many of them. For example,
Arzurum was a Roman city. This city
here, Arzurum. Um, and so many more.
I'll not I'll not go into the details.
And then you have nations like Armenia,
which Turkey wants to wipe off the map
of the world. And Turkey is using
Azarbaijan as a proxy to do this to
Armenia. The great dream that Turkey has
is to create a panuran corridor wiping
Armenia off the map of the world and
creating this this corridor all the way
from Turkey to the Turkish central Asian
nations like Turkmanistan, Usbakistan,
Kazakhstan and so on. The only Central
Asian nation, Central Asian nation which
is not Turk is Tajakistan which is an
Indo-Iranian nation. So the Turks want
to do that. Now Turkey is a well this is
a see you could argue that this is
something that's happening far away from
India. What's the distance from here to
let's say Turkey? It's about 2 and a
half thousand kilometers. Okay from from
India to Turkey roughly. So why does
this concern India is what many people
would possibly ask naively and I don't
blame you for it because you may not
know about it. The thing is that Turkey
has consistently supported Pakistan and
they have consistently uh supported
Pakistan's terrorist activities against
India and Pakistan's illegal
illegitimate claims to Jammu and
Kashmir. Turkey has consistently
supported that and Turkey also sells
weapons to Pakistan.
Okay, drones and whatnot and maybe
there's intelligence sharing, maybe
there's other other stuff also that's
happening. So that's the deal and that's
the problem. So now for the longest time
we were a soft nation, a soft state and
we just simply uh accepted all all that
happened to us passively. But now this
government the Modi government is not
that sort of government and we are no
longer sitting back passively and
allowing things to happen. So what India
is doing so okay now now that we we have
discussed this let's uh remove that.
Here we are back here. Uh and where's
the question? So the question is what is
India doing? So first of all we we have
been supplying various kinds of weapons
to Armenia which is a very ancient
nation with old ties with our our
civilization and this nation is simply
trying to survive and Turkey wants to
wipe it out. Turkey and Azarbaijan want
to gang up and wipe Armenia out. So
India is supplying various kinds of very
potent weapons to Armenia. First of all
we have radars, Swati radars. Then we
have the the Pinaka multiarrel system
which is a very dangerous very scary uh
rocket system. Then the Akash system
which is a battle tested probably the
best anti- uh aircraft air defense
system in the world right the Akash
system. So we are supplying these
weapons to Armenia
through Iran. I mean the deliveries are
said to have happened via Iran. Very
interesting. So Iran and India, Iran is
a Islamic nation. India is a Hindu
nation. So an Islamic nation is teaming
up with a Hindu nation to ensure the
survival of a Christian nation which is
Armenia. Very interesting stuff that's
happening. And who is supporting Turkey
and Azarbaijan? Two two Sun two Sunni
Islamic nations. It's the Jewish nation
Israel that's supporting them.
Israel is supporting Azarbaijan and by
extension Turkey. So in Israel and India
are on opposite sides of the war here.
Do you understand? They're on opposite
sides of the conflict.
So uh to answer the question of the
civilizational warrior here, there's no
point there. there's no way we can
create this military partnership which
includes Israel
because Israel is is working with Turkey
and Azarbaijan
and and they are working towards wiping
Armenia off the map of the world. So
Israel is not going to be in this
coalition in this partnership but we are
partnering with Turkey. So what am I
saying? We are partnering with Greece
with Cypress. Cypress is a Greek region
with Greece with with Cypress and with
Armenia
and uh we will most likely be possibly
potentially
uh supplying weapons to Greece as well.
We have very good weapons. Uh so that's
the situation. So we are creating an
anti-Turic coalition of nations. We are
supporting all the nations that are that
Turkey is threatening
and we are we are doing legitimate arms
sales. We're not doing anything hanky
pangy, anything uh that is not allowed
by international law. So perfectly good,
perfectly fine. Um
so yeah, what we're doing goes against
the interest of Turkey because Turkey
has been going against our interest for
decades.
Um so this does expand our geopolitical
leverage beyond the Indian subcontinent.
it goes now our our our leverage if you
want to call it that will extend to the
Mediterranean region the eastern
Mediterranean region and the in Greece
and Cyprus and all that yeah it is a
welldeserved tip for that response to
Turkey now we're going to take it
further I'm sure we are becoming um um
notable arms exporter we are not not yet
a major arms exporter but we have
weapons very good weapons battle tested
weapons that many countries now desire
they want. Right? So we are certainly
going into that. I am pretty sure we
will not sell the Brahmos to Greece,
Cyprus or Armenia because of various
reasons, but we will definitely sell
various kinds of cruise missiles and
anti-aircraft systems to these nations
and possibly other kinds of missiles.
We'll see. So yeah, it's I think it's
it's these are very good moves by India.
Right. Next question.
This is by Ubendran.
Historically, China has lost every
single war it fought on Chinese soil.
That's a good point you make. It's a
point I've been making for a while, for
a while, for years. So in a in a
hypothetical scenario, if suddenly war
erupts between India and China, if we
take the war inside Chinese territory,
if Indian soldiers enter into China,
let's say we invade Tibet and we have
taken the war inside Chinese mainland,
can we win? And also please explain what
the current political situation in
China. Many things should be happening
inside Chinese politics at the moment.
Okay, we're going to discuss the the the
China factor.
You are right. uh China has historically
lost all wars they have had to fight on
their own territory when they have
invaded other nations. They have in the
past won on some occasions. I mean the
last war China fought was in 1979 where
China attempted an invasion of Vietnam
and that was a war China lost. China got
a beating. China got a bloody nose in
that war. Little Vietnam compared to
China. Vietnam is little little Vietnam
beat up the Chinese, defeated the
Chinese. It was a disaster. It was a
very bad start, you could say, to Deng
Shopping's political career, not his
career as the as the leader of China,
but anyhow, he was able to recover from
that. Um, but in the past, for example,
1962, they attempted an invasion of
India and they were able to capture some
Indian territory, which they still hold.
That was a victory. It was it was defeat
for India. 1967 they tried something
else and that's a war they lost to India
in 1987 or something. Sundarang Chu or
whatever it was that was
uh
that that was another set of battles the
Chinese lost to India and so on. Uh but
historically I mean go back the past
2,000 plus years whenever somebody has
made the Chinese fight on their own
territory which means China was invaded.
Whenever that's happened, the Chinese
have lost. That's a pattern. I mean, I
did this podcast a few years ago with
Dr. Edward Lutwak,
and he said that all it takes to defeat
China is three guys on horseback. Okay,
it's a humorous statement to make, but
it's kind of true. You you need three
guys on horseback if you want to defeat
China. You need to get into into Chinese
territory, the Chinese will lose. So,
that's the pattern. That's a humorous
way of putting it but it's it's kind of
true. So now the question is okay let's
let's uh where's where is map? Yes we we
will see the map. Uh here we have the
map. So north of India we have Tibet.
Chinese occupied Tibet and Chinese
occupied Singinjang. Singinjang was
historically Kushan territory. Tibet was
obviously historically and has always
been Tibetan territory and so on. Um the
real China lies over here. All of this
territory north of India is Chinese
occupied territory. It's not really
Chinese territory. Um
so the question is if there's a war in
the future between India and China and
we take the war inside Chinese territory
then what happens? Do we can we win? The
point is this. See China has no love for
Tibet or Shinjang. These are not Chinese
territories. They these territories are
valuable for China because of the
natural resources available water very
important natural resource uranium rare
earths copper all kinds of resources are
available in the region and that's why
these regions are important for China
and also because it gives the China a
territorial advantage right these are
the reasons why these are the reasons
why these regions are important to China
but these are not Chinese territories
let's say we cross over into Tibet and
we we capture let's say Lassa. Well,
it's it's a setback for China, but it's
not Chinese territory. The real Chinese
territory is here. Okay? And the Chinese
don't care about the population in Tibet
or Shinjang. If those people something
happens to them, the Chinese will not
weep for them. So, if you want to really
defeat China, you have to fight on
actual Chinese territory, which is these
regions. Zanadu,
Shanyang,
Chongqing, Yangyang,
Xingyang, Cha and so on.
Okay, that's how you defeat the Chinese.
But the point is, look, we don't have
those expeditionary forces that can
fight so deep into Chinese territory. So
my point is, if there's a war between
India and China, we have to not allow
the Chinese to cross the LC. We have to
cross the LAC, take the battle into
Tibet. the the the supply lines for
China are very very like it's it's easy
to cut those off. Obviously, the Chinese
have certain advantages like strategic
bombers and whatnot, but it's not that
difficult to ch to cut off Chinese
supply lines into Tibet and the Chinese
positions in Tibet are pretty exposed.
The Chinese have been doing their best.
I will show you if you like what they've
been doing north of the LAC. Let us let
us let us do that. Let's let's take a
look at the Chinese positions north of
the LAC. I mean right above the LAC.
Let's do that. So let's go to for
example uh the Ladak region. Okay. Uh
where is Ladak? This is Ladak. If we go
to the Pangong lake for example,
the Chinese have positions uh north of
the Pangong
right north of Pangong. Uh so where is
our place called uh Chushul? Okay, north
of Chushul. If we go north of the lake,
there are Chinese positions here.
And if I were to look here, look at look
at the Chinese entrenchments. These are
Chinese bases, okay? Military bases. You
can see they are well dug in. They have
created these these little mounds over
here. Uh almost like trench warfare.
Look at all these positions. This is
like very well entrenched and they it's
like they they are prepared to fight a
defensive uh battle over here.
As you can see over here, it's not just
buildings, but they have created this
these mounds around the buildings to to
ensure survivability. Look at this here.
See all of this. These are all Chinese
positions. And they have look at this.
Look at these bunkers that they have
built over here. Very well done. So,
it's very difficult to just wipe them
off even through missile strikes or
Brahmo strikes because they are well
spread out.
Uh if you look here these lines of
bunkers you will find and I can just go
on I can I can do a 1 hour tour of the
Chinese positions uh north of Pangong.
They have they even have these uh these
positions right off the lake. They have
created these roads over here. They they
are supposed to have boats and even many
submarines in the region. As you can see
the lake is frozen over here and so on.
Uh so the point is if you if you want to
defeat the Chinese in a future war you
have to take the fight into Chinese
occupied Tibet and Chinese occupied
Shinjang. It's not enough to simply
fight a defensive war. You have to
defeat them on territory they control
and occupy. So yeah that's the situation
and that's the deal.
Uh Nazif Nazifa Rahman says happy guru.
Oh well thank you so much ma'am. Uh what
do you think of the recent lowquality
BBC report of Shik Hassina? So the BBC
has recently come out. Let's let's do a
Google search. What is the BBC claiming?
Uh let us see. Let's do a Google search.
BBC Shikh Hasina. They have come out
with a report recently which which
alleges that Shik Hasina authorized
violence against students. BBC Shik
Hassina
Shik Hassina BBC see Shik four days ago
Shikh Hassina authorized deadly
Bangladesh crackdown leaked audio
suggests see they they are covering
their backsides by saying by using the
word suggests
so they are not really
uh owning up and they're not really uh
saying that it it confirms they're
saying it suggests So that way they can
say that you know we did not make a
definite claim. We simply say said that
this so-called leak audio suggests that
Bangladesh leader Assena authorized this
deadly crackdown. Uh so it's it's it's
very poor very lowquality journalism.
Anybody can create a voice clone of
somebody.
It will cost you what like nothing to
create a voice clone of somebody and and
have any any kind of said thing that is
spoken. You can create a voice clone of
Osh Kasina and have that voice clone AI
generated voice clone say anything you
want
and the question is how did they obtain
this nonsense? Who gave it to them? Is
that person is that source reliable?
Have you disclosed the sources? No, we
don't disclose our sources. Our sources
are confidential. Then you're just
making up stories, right?
the BBC well you know the BBC
it's it's a tool of the deep state it's
a tool of the US it it serves the the
geopolitical agenda and they have this
they've always had this great hatred
towards India and Shri Kasina was pro-
India which is why they hate her by
extension uh so my what's my view on
this I think this is nonsense we don't
need to take it seriously we should not
take this nonsense seriously
uh the Question is if India had not
developed nukes how would our relations
with the US be today as Dr. Abdul Gulam
said only strength respects strength. Uh
okay.
Well, if he did say that he is
absolutely correct obviously right
strength respect respects strength. Uh
imagine a world in which India doesn't
have nuclear weapons.
See
why is the US giving special
consideration to India right now. Trump
has made all kinds of threats against
India, tariff threats and whatnot. And
he imposed the July 9 deadline to on
India for a trade deal with the US.
Well, today is July what 12th, right?
The July 9 deadline has come and gone.
We have refused to sign a trade deal
with the US. Has he imposed any tariffs
on us? He has not. And he's saying that
maybe in the next 48 or so hours there's
going to be a mini trade deal which will
be the first step towards a a more
comprehensive trade deal down the road.
But he has imposed 50% tariffs on Brazil
which is a US vasal. He's imposed
tariffs on Canada. I think 40% tariffs
on Canada. Another US vasal. He has
imposed I don't know what tariffs 15% or
whatever it is on Japan and South Korea.
He's imposing he's essentially
conducting a trade war against his own
allies and was but he has backed down
when it comes to India. Now what does it
mean? Is he afraid of Indian nuclear
weapons? He's not.
But India is super valuable to the US
because the Chinese are afraid of us of
Indian nuclear weapons. You understand
that if India did not have nuclear
weapons today, India would nobody would
think of India. You may have the fourth
largest economy in the world, but if you
don't have that hard edge that nukes
bring, nobody cares. You're a soft
state. Your economy it's is is is it's
good for nothing unless you can defend
the economy.
And the ultimate defense is nuclear
weapons and the means to deliver those
nuclear weapons. So if India had did not
have nukes today, nobody would take
India seriously. Nobody would take Prime
Minister Modi seriously. Nobody would
take us seriously at all. India would be
just another soft state. Look at what
happened to Iran. Iran has been
developing nuclear capabilities for
decades. But they have always been
afraid to take the final step. So see
what happened to them. A little Israel
came and beat them up and then Donald
Trump dumped bunker busting bombs on
their facilities, nuclear facilities for
Natans, for Iswahan and so on.
Can someone dare to do that to India?
Not possible.
So if India had not developed nukes,
then India would be in a very difficult
situation today. Very very vulnerable
position today. So yeah, at least that's
one good thing we did back in the day.
Right.
Right. Okay.
So Khadaka says Pong Shinawatra's audio
leak was a planned leak or was it okay?
Was this a planned leak or was this an
accidental thing? She seems like Miss
Sana Marin today was my dick. This was
leaked. So here's the situation. I've
explained this in great detail on one of
my previous geost strategy episodes. The
the border dispute between uh Cambodia
and Thailand. It's not a border dispute.
It's a temple dispute. Okay, let's let's
put that on the screen. I'll just
quickly cover this today. So, the entire
controversy
was all about the Thailand Cambodia
border dispute. The Priya Vihar temple.
Priya Vihar temple. So, here it is. So
let's first zoom out to see where it is
located. It's between Thailand and
Cambodia. It's an ancient Shiva temple
that was built by a Kmare king a
thousand years ago, King Surya.
And if you look here,
you can see this is a very it's a pretty
extensive ancient temple. Multiple goas.
The government of India is helping
restore one of the Gopuras over here.
Okay. It's a pretty extensive temple. It
was a shite temple. It's built on top of
a hill and both nations claim it. Both
nations, as you can see, this is a hill.
It's a small hilly hilly place. And both
nations claim this territory, this
temple, not the territory, the temple.
And both nations have almost essentially
gone to the brink of war for this
temple. It's it's a ruined temple.
There's nothing uh of of of value from a
western perspective over here. It's a
ruined temple, thousand years old.
But both nations rever this temple and
it's not even a Buddhist temple. Both
nations are officially Buddhist nations.
This is a Hindu temple, a Shiva temple.
But both nations claim it and both
nations want it no matter what the cost.
Okay. So now this is and in 2008 the
nations the two nations went to the
brink of war for the temple. Then the
ICG came in the way and gave the temple
to Cambodia. But there was some language
in the judgment that is still kind of uh
um a little ambiguous and that's why
this thing has carried on. And earlier
this year there was another border clash
firing on both sides. I think at least
one or two soldiers died
and the whole thing became tense again.
So the prime minister of of Thailand her
name is Mrs. Pythan Shinavatra. She
comes from a very prominent uh political
family. Her dad was prime minister of
Thailand. I think one of her siblings
was prime minister of Thailand and so
on. So she is the prime minister of
Thailand. The leader of Cambodia is a
gentleman called Hunen. He is the well
still the leader you could say. Uh let's
let's quickly look up Mr. Hunen.
So first of all let's look up pay
to shinata. This is the lady who is now
no longer uh the prime minister of uh
Cambodia. And let's look at Mr. Hunen.
So he's the man. He's the man, the
strong man. When I was a kid, he was
this young army soldier. I remembered
him. This is what he looked like. And
now he's a pretty elderly elder
statement uh statesman of Cambodia. He's
no longer the the president or whatever
it is, but he is still the most powerful
man in the country.
And he was previously the prime minister
of Cambodia. So he's the guy you talk to
if you want to have um any diplomatic
meaningful diplomatic dialogue with
Cambodia. The highest level is Mr.
Hunen. So Python Shinawatra when while
she was prime minister she spoke on the
phone with Mr. Hunen about this
territorial dispute
and looks like Mr. Hunen recorded that
and in this phone conversation she was
very
polite very differential to Mr. Hunsen,
she called him uncle and she kind of
criticized her military and their
behavior and Mr. Hunen leaked this. So
it was not accidental, it was a planned
leak and he brought her down and uh
yeah, so now you have another situation
in Thailand. So that's the whole deal.
So behind the context of all of this is
the territorial dispute. The dispute
over this ancient Hindu temple Shiva
temple which both nations claim and
Cambodia currently has control over.
Okay. Amisha says please explain Chingis
Khan's genetic legacy. Is it true that
one in 200 men are direct descendants of
Shri Chingis Khan? This is a myth that
has gone on for more than 20 years. I
think it was in 2003 that I think it was
National Geographic or whoever that
published a report based on some genetic
research. They claimed that one in 200
men is a descendant of Chingish Khan
based on genetic information. So there
is this there's the concept of a haplo
group. I've discussed it lots of times.
Let me once again tell you what a haplo
group is. A haplo group is a group of
people who are alive today and they all
have they all descend from one single
individual
who lived several centuries ago and that
individual in that individual there was
a genetic mutation that was then passed
down
and the the hypo group is the group of
people who all share that genetic
mutation which originated in a single
person in the past. So it's a genetic
lineage essentially a haplo group. The
most prominent most widespread haplo
group is called R1 A1A or R - R M17
which has very significant number of
people in India and a very significant
people of number of people in Eastern
Europe and this is supposed to be the
believed to be the HLO group that was
responsible for the spread of the
Indo-Uropean languages and so on.
There's a big controversy about the
origin of R1 A1A. Was it in Europe? Was
it in Central Asia? Was it in India? And
that's the crux of the RN invasion
theory. Lots of people talk about that
and it's not really the the right way to
look at it, but that's different story.
So when it comes to this issue of
Chingghis Khan,
um there was a there was a 2003
research paper I believe that National
Geographic referenced in which there
they found they discovered that a very
large number of people in Eurasia and
all the way into the Pacific Islands
they descend from a single haplo they're
all members of a single haplo group
whose origin was in Mongolia about a
thousand years ago.
Now Chunghis Khan lived about 800 years
ago roughly 850 years ago. I think
around that time he was born. So that's
close enough right?
So to publicize the paper they claimed
that this was Chingis Khan who was the
originator of the Haplau group and he's
the guy who's the ancestor of millions
of people today. But that was completely
wrong. Why was it completely wrong?
The first question is what proof did
these researchers have that one man
Chingis Khan was the originator of the
haplo group. What proof did they have to
conclusively
prove that Chingis Khan was the
originator? They would need his DNA,
right? They would need his DNA. They
would need a piece of hair, a fragment
of bone, some kind of physical sample of
his body. And that's not available
because Chingish Khan's body has never
been found. His resting place has never
been found and I promise you it will
never be find found.
So they don't have a single sample of
his DNA. They don't have any sing a
single sample of the DNA of his sons or
grandsons.
Absolutely nothing. So how can they
claim that this group of people was
descended from Chingis Khan?
We know that this haplo group it
originated about about a thousand years
ago. That's what this uh study in 2003
showed. But then there was another re
research that was done in 2018 I think
in which they showed that this haplo
group actually originated about 2,300
years ago.
So the ind the original person in which
this genetic mutation happened that
person lived about 2,300 years ago.
So then where's the then it completely
destroys this claim that Changish Khan
was the originator of the Haplo group.
Now clearly the HLO group originated in
Mongolia and the Mongols are nomadic
people and they spread all across the
world especially after the rise of
Chingis Khan. Mongol soldiers spread all
across Eurasia and in a few short years
after Shingistan's death they were
occupying Russia and obviously there's
going to be genetic intermingling of
people there.
So it's it's and lots of Mongols
eventually became Muslims in in the Turk
regions and they became Turkishized
Turkified. So these Mongolian genes
would have spread all across Eurasia. It
has nothing to do with Chistan.
Jingish Khan had a handful of children,
four sons. Uh what are the names? Uh
Chagatai
Ogadeay.
Uh and and two more. Uh yeah, I forget
right now. And he had some daughters as
well, obviously. That's that's from his
his queen. Uh her name was Borth. Borte.
And I'm sure that he had other other
concubines as well, but her children
were never in line for the succession
obviously. So maybe let's say he had 50
children or 100 children. Even then it
doesn't explain this the widespread of
this of of Mongolian genetics which
originates in 2000 uh about 2,300 years
ago. So this entire story that Chingis
Khan was a prolific
father of children or whatever this is a
complete myth absolute myth and there
have been you know people have twisted
this story to claim that he was a
prolific rapist which is once again
absolutely untrue utterly untrue.
If you look at the Mongolian law that he
had applied across the lands he
controlled,
assaulting a woman in any way was was
punishable with death. Okay. So,
and he would have no moral authority to
uphold such laws if he himself did not
if he himself broke those laws. And so,
the point is this is this is all a lie.
It's not true that one in 200 men are
direct descendants of Changist Khan. He
surely I'm sure has lots of descendants
who are alive today all the way from
Russia all all the way to I'm sure
Eastern Asia but I am sure any man who
lived a thousand years ago will have
thousands tens of thousands of
descendants today or woman for the sake
for that matter
so uh this this urban myth about
Changistan is completely false and it's
it's it's sad that you know someone of
somebody like him is maligned in this
manner that the west hates non-western
people who succeed and Chinghan was the
was greater than Alexander and clearly
certainly less brutal and less cruel
than Alexander but they have portrayed
Chingghistan as the most brutal and
crulest king of all and Alexander as
some kind of saint
you know great Alexander the great but
Chingishan was greater than Alexander he
had a greater territory greater empire
he achieved so much more but he's not
called Ching is the great.
So that is how it goes. You see bias
says how did we end in agriculture from
hunting? Mr. Yual Noa No Yu Harari said
that hunting is pretty easy compared to
farming which is why transforming from
hunting to agriculture is unlikely. What
are my thoughts?
Well, if that was the case, why did the
whole world take up agriculture? How
were there multiple Neolithic
revolutions? Uh the the origin of
agriculture in the Indian subcontinent
goes back 17 18,000 years and there's
plenty of evidence of this in the
Gangetic region, the Ganga plane, the
Ganga Valley about 13,000 years before
today. And then there was a neo there
was this Neolithic revolution in the
fertile crescent region which is between
the two rivers, the Euphrates and the
Tigris that happened about 10,000 years
ago apparently. And then there was an
independent Neolithic revolution
in South America.
Um the Inca the the the ancestors of the
Inca Empire they had an independent
Neolithic revolution that goes back
about 10,000 years.
So people discovered agriculture
independently of each other. First of
all in the Indian subcontinent then in
the fertile crescent west Asia and then
at the same time as west Asia
independently another such thing in uh
South America.
So if
hunting was so easy why did people take
up agriculture is the question.
So first of all hunting is not easy. I I
have no idea what Mr. Hari has said.
Okay. I have not read his books. I have
his books but I haven't read them.
Sorry. I have so many books I haven't
read. I buy them but I sometimes don't
end up reading some of them and they
this they they serve as a reminder to me
that I have so much more to learn. My
point is see I know that Harari's books
are are very popular etc and I don't
really know what he has said. The point
is is hunting that easy
really is it is easy you hunting animals
sometimes hunting is super dangerous. If
you're hunting mammoths my goodness a
mammoth is a frightening animal. If
you're hunting, let's say a rabbit,
well, rabbits are super quick. They're
very hard to hunt. Hunting means you're
trying to kill animals and those animals
have no intention of being killed. Of
course, we are superior in intelligence,
so we find ways of doing it. But it's
not easy. It's very difficult. You have
to chase animals for for days, weeks
sometimes. And u often very difficult,
often very dangerous. Often you die.
Often there are other predators who want
to eat the same animal and they don't
want you to to get the animal. So
they'll come and eat you.
We have found ancient human skulls with
bite marks in the orbital bones and the
bite marks exactly matched the teeth of
cats, large cats like leopards.
Sometimes we found humans who have been
prayed upon by eagles, the claw marks on
the on the skulls and so so on. It was
not easy.
And when you are a hunter, you can never
have a big big group of people living
together because hunting it's something
you may succeed doing like once in two
three days and it can never sustain a
large population. So I think hunting is
actually very difficult. It's good
physically if you're a hunter and you're
eating meat. You're going to be lean and
thin. You will never be obese. You'll
never have excess food. You always hand
to mouth. Always you need to hunt. That
sort of thing. But agriculture once it
was discovered it made life so easy. You
did not have to run hundreds of
kilometers looking for prey for animals
to hunt. You just needed good land.
Settle down,
plant your crops and live there. Of
course, there's going to be continuous
labor required on a daily basis as long
as the crop cycle goes on. So that
became a specialized
uh field, right? agriculture specialized
occupation, but you did not have to take
huge risks. You do not have to chase
animals. You just needed to spend a few
hours in the field every day. And you
were guaranteed large quantities of of
of grain cereal, which is why humans
shifted from a protein and fat-based
diet to a carbohydrate-based diet.
And when you have fields that guarantee
essentially food cycle after cycle, you
can then start building large societies
and your population can grow. And when
you humans settle down together, culture
evolves, civilization evolves. So that
is how agriculture transformed human
society.
It's not unlikely. It's very it makes a
lot of sense for that to happen. Okay.
Uh so as long as we were hunters, our
ancestors were all hunters. They used to
eat, they used to hunt animals and and
subsist of that, that was a very tough
life. We still have hunter gatherer
societies in some parts of the world.
Look at the state, their condition.
They're still very primitive compared to
agricultural societies.
We have hunter gatherers in the
so-called Sentinel Island in the Andaman
Nicobar region, right? We have hunter
gatherers who are still uncontacted in
parts of Papwa Newu Guinea in in the
Amazon rainforest and so on. They live
very primitive lives. Their lives are
very tough. You'll never see uh a plump
person who's a hunter gatherer. They're
always lean and kind of malnourished.
That's not easy. It's very difficult.
Once you once we made the transition to
farming, hunting was always an option.
And then that's how animal agriculture
came into the thing and so and so on. Uh
so it was the transition from hunting
from being hunter gatherers to being
agriculturalists
that created
uh stable societies, permanent
settlements. It gave rise to proper
culture and eventually high civilization
and we our ancestors in the subcontinent
were the first to do that. Is true. Yes.
Uh Sheras says how do you see the debate
on arian origins evolving in the next
dec decade till 2035 given the
advancements in genetics archaeology and
linguistics
look the turning point is the
decipherment of the industry now
obviously many people still don't
believe what has done
it'll take time but eventually I mean
it's going to come out it's it's it's
going to have to be accepted so the
decipherment
of this long
undeciphered script is a landmark
development
and it's Sanskrit it's it's Vic Sanskrit
that's the end of the RN invasion debate
you can keep crying genetics this
genetics that archaeology this whatever
this is the crucial factor the central
claim of the first of all the central
claim of the arvision myth is twofold
that Hinduism is foreign to India and
Sanskrit is foreign to India And they
claim that the Arian invasion or
migration or picnic or tourism whatever
happened around 1500 BC
around 1500 BC when the great river was
drying out.
Now if Hinduism, evil Hinduism and evil
Sanskrit came into India around 1500 BC
then how come these inscriptions from
from 5,000 6,000 years ago are in
Sanskrit
the Harapan Indust Valley inscriptions.
How come they're in Sanskrit? That
destroys this theory once and for all.
Now the question is how when will this
be
accepted academically in a widespread
manner that will take 20 30 years maybe
but you can't now do a thing about this.
The decipherment is out in the public
domain. Try and pro prove it wrong. Try
and prove it wrong.
Try and prove it is some proto some
other language. Simply can't happen.
It's it's done. So the debate in the RN
Asian thing, you know, people are going
to try and obscate the debate. They're
going to try and say it's going to be
proven genetically. How do you prove
culture and language genetically? The
origin of culture genetically?
How? If an if a person converts to a
foreign religion, does it change their
genetics?
H if an Indian person today converts to
a foreign religion for whatever reason,
will it change their genetics? If an
Indian person starts speaking a foreign
language like I'm doing right now, does
it change my genetics? No. So genetics
has no connection with culture, religion
or language. So how do you prove that so
and so genetic uh marker
carries a certain language or family
language family or a certain religion?
You can't. You simply can't. It's an
assumption they are making. And you
can't do science on the basis of
assumptions. You can't. There has to be
hard empirical evidence. And there is
none whatsoever about the connection of
whatever genetic uh markers
with a certain language or a certain
culture or a certain religion so-called
step ancestry.
What was the origin of the step
ancestry?
Step ancestry goes back let's say 8,000
years or maybe 10,000 years. What was
the origin of that? Where were those who
were the ancestors of those people? They
did not spring out of the step right of
the ground. They also had ancestors who
came from somewhere. Where did those
ancestors come from? Let's go back to
the origin of everything. The origin of
everything is the Indian subcontinent.
The original
region where humanity settled down after
the out of Africa migration. So
th this debate will go on and lots of
low IQ people will keep on debating this
and even high IQ people will keep on
obiscating things. This is going to go
on for the next decade, two decades,
three decades.
What needs to be done to end this
genetic debate for example is the Indian
government needs to take the initiative
of properly of doing a proper genetic
survey of India at least 10,000 samples
at least from the across the length and
the breadth of the Indian subcontinent
as far as possible. If Pakistan doesn't
want to participate to hell with them
we'll go and talk with Taliban.
They run Afghanistan. We would like some
genetic samples of the various Afghan
populations. We can do the same for
Bangladesh, same for Nepal, same for
Bhutan, same for Sri Lanka, same for the
Maldives and obviously the rest of the
subcontinent is India at least 10,000
samples and let's do a proper proper
genetic survey and look into the deep
ancestry of the people of the
subcontinent. This all these categories
that have been created this ancestral
north Indian, ancestral south Indian,
all of these categories have been
created by foreigners.
We need to own our genetic research.
They've had this project in the past.
This 10,000 genomes project. We need to
have our own such project but only for
the subcontinent.
And we can also have various south
various other nations participate if if
they want to in a second phase. For
example, Southeast Southeast Asian
nations Cambodia, Indonesia, Malaysia,
Thailand. Oh, that will be very
interesting. The connections will come
out. and also central Asia, Tajakistan
for example. If Persia wants to
participate, sure please. We we would
love to. So that's what we need to do.
But it has to happen in India with
Indian scientists and Indian research.
Once you do that, all this nonsense
that's coming from the west will
evaporate. It'll it'll it'll end once
and for all. But this takes time and
money.
And right now we are I'm sure that the
government has other uh priorities
perhaps. So whenever this happens, it'll
it'll end the end this entire matter
once and for all. All right. And I would
love for this to happen at the earliest.
Okay.
Donar Singh Johan says, "Was Einstein
overhyped because of the rich Jews
backing him?" Well, well, well. I've
heard that Herbert Dingle, for example,
criticized Einstein's theory of
relativity and wrote extensively about
it, pointing u some very potential
flaws, but was never given any
importance in by the mainstream
scientists. Well, that's that's
terrible. Uh so what's the deal? So what
does it mean to overhype somebody? If
somebody's overhyped, it means that that
person is given a lot of attention which
that person doesn't deserve.
Now when it comes to a scientist,
what does it mean that a scientist is
overhyped? It means that that
scientist's theory has been given too
much attention, too much prominence
which it does not deserve. Which
essentially means that this theory
probably is flawed. It is wrong. But we
are portraying it as correct. Right? So
now when it comes to science, it's so
easy to prove whether somebody is
overhyped or not.
All you have to ask yourself is, is his
theory true? Is it correct?
Obviously, it's the most correct theory
in history, general relativity.
Every no theory has been tested as much
as general relativity. And how do you
test a theory? By trying to disprove it.
By trying to prove that it's wrong.
That's how you test a theory. There are
tests ongoing right now.
No theory has been tested the way
general relativity has.
If general relativity was was incorrect,
GPS satellites would not work today.
The GPS satellites have relativistic
corrections without which they would
give us wrong information.
General relativity is the most
successful scientific theory in human
history apart from quantum field theory.
Okay. So Einstein was not overhyped. He
deserves every bit of hype he has got
and more. Please understand that. Now
Herbert Dingle, he was a physicist
himself, English English man. He was
born in the late 19th century I believe
and he was a spectroscopist
and he also wrote a book about
astrophysics. Um
and he he entered into feuds with
various physicists. For example, Arthur
Edington, uh, Edward Mil, he entered
into feuds with those people. He
criticized their theories, claimed those
were wrong. Um, but nothing came of it.
And then he went after Einstein and he
said that relative relativity was wrong.
He said that special relativity was
incorrect, not general relativity. Uh,
and it looks like he uh was not very
clear about the concepts of relativity.
What is an event relativistically in the
theory of relativity? What what does it
mean? What is an event? And what is
simultaneity?
What's it what does it mean for for two
events to be simultaneous?
These are very basic fundamental core
concepts in relativity. Okay. And in
relative relativity, you have something
called frames. Frames of reference. And
generally we speak about inertial
frames. frames that are not
accelerating.
And in relativity, the theory says that
every frame has its own uh standard of
simultaneity.
So two events that may be simultaneous
in one frame may not happen
simultaneously in a different frame of
reference. That's a deal. Uh so that
seems to be something that Mr. Dingle,
Dr. Dingle, Herbert Dingle seems to have
not been clear about. and he spent
essentially his life uh criticizing
relativity and I believe lots of
physicists pointed it out to him that
you need to get your fundamentals
correct but uh he was not he probably
did not want that. Um and
I think there are many videos on YouTube
in which Herbert Dingle is cited as as
as the guy who pointed out that Einstein
was wrong. Well, Einstein was not wrong.
And I I know there are some other
scientists also who claim that Einstein
made blunders and he was wrong. Um
that's not the case. Einstein was a
genuine genius. In one year he
revolutionized physics. 1905 Anus
Mirabilis
quantum field uh quantum mechanics and
special relativity at the same time and
the photoelectric effect which also was
which has a quantum foundation. So it
was uh quantum theory the the the the
concept of the light quantum the quantum
of light. I mean nobody imagined life
light itself would have a quantum and so
so all of that he he put out in 1905 an
incredible year and how can anybody
imagine that Einstein was overhyped and
the let's not bring religion into this.
Yes he was Jewish. I'm not sure of who
backed him or who did not but come on.
So please understand you cannot bring in
other biases into your consideration of
whether a person his scientific output
was correct or not. This is not a
religious matter. Um he was the greatest
physicist of the 20th century and one of
the greatest physicists of all time. No
question about it.
Okay.
Uh you see she says yesterday I met a
girl who was saying that the cast thing
is because of our religion. Our religion
is obviously very evil, right? Very
backward, primitive and so on. So in the
cast, oh my god, we have cast terrible.
And so this this cast thing according to
this girl was because of our religion. I
tried to explain that this was a
colonial imposition. But she kept on
referring to a variety of books. Of
course, there are lots of books written
about cast which all said that Indians
are evil, Hinduism is evil and so on. Uh
so she referred to a variety of books to
prove her stance. Can you please tell us
in detail how Jati Verna system was like
and how was there really discrimination
as it is generally shown in the media
and all. Now I have I'm not going to
answer the question directly because
I've answered this so many times. So let
me show you how to find what I have had
to say about this. Okay. Go to Google
search for Bridget Shava YouTube.
Okay. Then you go to the channel
and let's go to the channel and uh there
is going to be this search box over
here.
Okay. So just type in cast.
Let's type in cast. So what do we have
here? I have spoken about these these
matters many times. Uh India's cast
system is a colonial imposition. This is
a 7.545
7 minute plus segment over here.
Donachari versus Eklavia in karna is
that castism cast system mental
coronization 11 minutes I've spoken
about it dowi etc um and so on
so I I have answered these questions
multiple times I don't think there's a
point
me answering it all over again doing the
same saying the same thing over and over
again so my point is for those of you
who are new to the channel this channel
has been in operation since what
actively since 200 2021. I have answered
thousands of questions as part of the
Ask a Widget Show. I have put out
thousands of clips on the channel, at
least more than 1500 clips of the of the
answers I've given. And if you are
curious about what I have had to say
about something, just go to my channel.
There's a search box there. Type in your
search term and most likely I will have
answered your question. So as you can
see in that thing that we saw I've
already answered the question at least
two three times and I've actually
answered it more than two three times
but I'll put out two three clips of it.
So please check it out and you will know
what I've had to say in this. I've
referred to various books also and I've
got those books here and there but uh
well I'll not go and search for them
right now. So check it out please do
that.
Okay. Rahul says what would happen if a
B2 bomber is made supersonic? Would it
lose its stealth? Uh when the design
when the design and paint determines how
stealthier
the aircraft is,
does speed also matter? Uh okay.
B2 bomber. What if we make it
supersonic? Right. Uh will it lose the
stealth?
So first of all, let's understand what
the whole thing is. a B2 bomber which
the Americans used to bomb Iran
recently. It's a stealth bomber and it's
a subsonic bomber which means that its
speed is less than the speed of sound.
Um the and it's a strategic bomber. It's
a long range long distance bomber. Okay.
A strategic bomber is a is a is an
aircraft which has a very long range
typically at least minimum 2,000 km
without refueling but with refueling it
can go maybe 10,000 kil kilometers or
more. So first of all it has a very long
range and secondly it has a very heavy
payload capacity.
It can probably you know some bombers
can carry about 100 tons of explosives.
100 tons of bombs that they can then use
to strike the adversaries strategic
targets which are targets like
industrial centers, transportation hubs,
military bases that are far from the
borders deep inside the country's
territory even nuclear facilities like
Iran. Okay. So the objective of
strategic bombers is to go deep beyond
enemy lines often and degrade the
enemy's warf fighting capacity and
probably the morale of the enemy. Uh so
that's a strategic bomber. Tactical
bombers have shorter ranges and they are
optimized for shorter short range
missions and probably support of
battlefield operations and so on. So a
strategic bomber goes and attacks deep
deep into the enemy's territory and it
attacks high value strategic targets and
so on long range and all those things
that I mentioned. So what's the why why
does a strategic bomber if you look at
the various strategic bombers that you
have in the world they typically have
short ru sorry uh they typically are
subsonic they are not supersonic
um for example there are various
American aircraft which which are uh
which are subsonic the B2 is a great
example of a subsonic bomber the B-52 is
rather old aircraft maybe pretty pretty
ancient aircraft which is still in
operation that is subsonic. Uh the
Russians have various subsonic aircraft
like the Tupolev 95 which is a turborop
aircraft does it doesn't have jet
engines so it has turborop engines. This
is a subsonic bomber. The Russians also
have a tupole tupole 160
uh which is a supersonic aircraft and
the Americans have a B1B I think B1B
which is supersonic. Uh but most
strategic bombers, long-range bombers
are subsonic because they need, see,
when you have a subsonic aircraft, it is
more fuel efficient. It gives you more
range for the same amount of fuel, which
makes a lot of sense. Secondly, if you
have a subsonic bomber, uh if if you
have a supersonic bomber, its airframe
needs uh requires thicker wings,
reinforced wings, and even the fuselage
needs to be thicker and and more
reinforced. So, because you the aircraft
needs to tolerate higher pressures,
higher more heating and all that. But if
it's a subsonic aircraft, it will not
need a thicker set of wings and a
thicker fuselage. So the fuel efficiency
is better, the range is better and so
on. Right? So all of those all of those
designs are in favor of subsonic
aircraft. And if you have a subsonic
aircraft, it's also optimized for better
uh met for maximum internal uh payload
volume. So you can have heavier payloads
in a subsonic aircraft uh and and so on.
So because of these things even the cost
complexity is is higher when you have uh
supersonic aircraft. So subsonic bombers
give you better range, they give you
better payload capacity, they give you
uh they are cheaper to maintain. Uh they
are less complex. They have longer
service lives and so on. And and uh
because of these reasons I think mostly
bombers are subsonic in nature. uh you
can have very high altitude flights
which would give it better survivability
and so on. So that's how uh strategic
bombers are are are made survivable. Now
if you take the B2 bomber and you turn
it into a supersonic aircraft, first of
all the design is such that it won't be
supersonic. It's got this wide flying
wing design, right? So you simply can't
make it supersonic. But if you let's say
take the F-35 which is a supersonic
stealth aircraft and you turn it into a
giant aircraft
will it work? No, it won't work at that
scale. We'll have to do some
modifications, right? And then once
again it's an extremely expensive
aircraft to maintain. It doesn't have
that amount of capacity, storage
capacity, you know, bomb bay capacity
and it it's it's going to be the
missions are going to be incredibly
expensive, incredibly complex.
So because of that strategic bombers are
typically subsonic. Uh you can try and
make a supersonic bomber but it it
u will it lose the stealth? You can
certainly have a stealthy aircraft which
is very expensive, very complicated but
it is supersonic and it is a strategic
bomber. Yeah. Um it will be stealthy but
it will be very expensive to maintain.
Um and what determines whether an
aircraft is is stealthy or not is the
design first of all the surfaces whether
they reflect radar or simply throw radar
waves off off uh
essentially don't return the radar waves
to the to the origin and secondly the
the the coating the surface material
also matters which is the paint the
paint or the coating of the aircraft. So
it is said that the F-35 whenever you
take it on a mission with the paint on
once it's back you need to repaint it
all over again and that is a process
that takes I don't know 20 30 40 50
hours per perhaps uh so speed matters of
course speed gives you survivability it
shortens the the length of missions it
gives you quick penetration into enemy
territory and so on but the payoff is is
that it you know the missions are way
more expensive you carry less payload
and so on. So it's this is a
hypothetical scenario that we are
considering. It's a very good question
that Rahul has asked. This is how you
understand things. This is how you break
things down into their elementary
concepts thinking from first principles.
Right? So you certainly can make a
supersonic bomber. The B2 can't be made
supersonic because it its shape its
design is by inherently subsonic.
Uh but you can have supersonic stealth
bombers but it doesn't make sense from a
cost perspective, from a mission
perspective, from payload perspective,
complexity perspective, uh you know
maintenance, lifetime perspective, so
many things.
Okay. Feminist etc. says to what extent
are a country's foreign policies
influenced by domestic, political,
economic and social priorities?
Conversely, how do foreign policy
decisions impact domestic affairs?
Any nation's foreign policy is
influenced by domestic policy and
domestic politics. Let's consider two
types of nations. A democracy and a
dictatorship. In a democracy, a prime
minister or president, whoever it is,
needs votes every four years, every 5
years. And if you mess up your foreign
policy, you're going to lose the
election, next election. So your foreign
policy has to be such that the public
will approve of it.
Okay? So it clearly tells you that your
domestic politics
influence and shape your foreign policy.
You can't have an unpopular foreign
policy. You're going to lose the next
election, right?
Uh if you're a dictator, you still need
some kind of public support. If you're
tremendously unpopular, they may rise up
and revolt against you. And you may be
able to crush the revolt, but it will
destroy your country's economy. It'll
waste so much of your resources. It's
bad for you. So, ideally, even if you're
a dictator, you want the people to be at
least visibly happy, even if they're
pretending to be happy, which means that
you cannot cross certain lines in
foreign policy, which would make you
unpopular.
So, foreign policies are always
influenced by domestic politics and
obviously politics is influenced by
social priorities, economics, and so
much more. So, all of that comes
together. Now, how do foreign policy
decisions impact domestic affairs? Well,
foreign policy decisions impact your
economy, which obviously impacts your
foreign uh your domestic affairs. Or
let's say for whatever reason you decide
that I'm going to be I'm going to make
my country a vasal of of a different
country. So once you make your country a
vasal of a more powerful nation, that
powerful nation makes inroads into your
domestic affairs and they may possibly
reshape your demographics. They may
start religious conversions in your in
your country. They may bring in foreign
infiltrators into your country. Look at
what's happening in the EU and so on. So
this obviously all of this has an impact
on all kinds of domestic matters
internally. So it's it's both ways
around. Okay.
Uh
Yum Tang Nabi says why are so many
Indians giving up their citizenship?
Many wealthy Indians are also leaving
India. Is it because of not being
provided a f favorable environment worth
the tax or some hidden geopolitics? What
do these people know that we are that we
don't? Is it a good decision? What would
be life outside India if you give up
your citizenship? Good and the bad and
so on. Why do people give up
citizenship? Because only first of all
only wealthy people can do it.
If you don't have the money and the
resources to become uh to purchase a
foreign citizenship then you you can't
do it. You can purchase foreign
citizenship or at least a green card, a
permanent residency kind of thing which
is a path to citizenship. Only wealthy
people can do it obviously, right? First
of all, you got to be wealthy. Why are
you leaving India? Because of the living
standards. Obviously, you want your kids
to grow up in a better environment. You
don't want your kids to uh be in an
education system where they have to face
reservations. You know, if you're a
general category, you don't want to deal
with the horrible roads. You don't want
to deal with the pollution. You don't
want to deal with the overcrowding. You
don't want to deal with the alleged
corruption everywhere allegedly. You
don't want to deal with all the issues,
right? So essentially you making a
selfish selfish decision that I'm going
to put prioritize myself and my family
first over the nation.
Um lots of Indians still love their
country even after they become foreign
citizens and so on. So is it's not
something that's about geopolitics. It's
not a geopolitical thing. It's a
personal choice. If you leave the
country and take up uh residency or
citizenship somewhere else, you don't
want to pay the odor as taxes in India.
Let's say I am uh let's say I'm let's
say earning okay hypothetically 1 cr a
year for hypothetical number and I'm
paying 30 lakhs income tax. Then I'm
going to buy a buy a car okay which
maybe let's say costs 30 lakhs. So I
have paid 30 lakhs income tax. I got 70
lakhs left of of my yearly salary. I
want to buy a car that costs 30 lakhs.
But I found that fine that it's GST etc
etc makes it a 50 lakh car. So I've
already paid tax now with the money
that's left from my after paying tax I
have to again pay more tax on a car that
would cost half the money outside and so
on. So eventually people give up. So
this only happens when you are
reasonably wealthy and if yeah so people
make a costbenefit analysis. I am paying
so much tax and let's say I mean for
example a flat will cost multiple crores
in a big city in India for the same
money you can buy a castle in a European
country
and it's it's just a that sort of thing
so that's why people are leaving it's a
personal choice some people choose to
despite the problems stay in India some
people say that okay I'm done I love my
country and my culture but I will live
outside of India good for my children
they will have a better life that sort
of
What is life outside of India? If you
give up citizenship, well, it's all over
the place. There are lots of Indians who
have given up citizenship, become
citizens of foreign countries, life
generally
if you give to if you go to a better
country where you have way better
standard of living, it's generally much
better, I suppose. But if you go to the
west, you will never be a first- class
citizen. You'll remain a secondass
citizen. And the west doesn't like
polytheists. So there are all kinds of
conditions and and considerations in
this matter.
Mudra Makwana says, "All politics aside,
which according to you is the best
country you admire that has great
culture, food, demographics, and natural
beauty where you visit and just love
being there except India of course. I
think Japan wins for me." Look,
there's no one country like that. Okay,
setting if you don't think about India
and ask yourself which are the other
good countries, there's no one country.
I I first of all, Japan is a great
choice. Japan is a wonderful country. Uh
I'm I'm a big fan of Japan. Great
history, great culture, great food,
great people, fantastic people. Uh
tragic history the past century or so.
Um and one hopes that emerges from
wherever. But it's a it's a wonderful
place. Uh big fan of Japan. Uh there are
so many other countries that are also
wonderful. I I if you ask me which is
your favorite book or your favorite
musician or favorite song, I don't have
any favorite one thing. I can give you a
set of 20 perhaps. So what are the great
countries? Greece is fantastic.
Beautiful. Beautiful country. Great
climate, great food, fantastic people,
great history, great ties with India
historically going back two and a half
thousand years. Greece is fantastic.
Italy fantastic country, very similar to
Greece in a lot of ways also neighbors
and so on. Italy is fantastic. Uh if you
look at Europe, Switzerland is a
beautiful country. Incredible natural
beauty, wonderful people. slightly
boring people but wonderful people, very
nice people. Um,
what else? Cypress is an extension of
Greece. So there you have that as also.
Um, in not far away the UA is a
wonderful place, the UAE, it's a it's
mostly desert but wonderful people, good
food, lots of great vegetarian options
by the way and there there's a lot of
natural beauty there also if you want to
look elsewhere. Mauritius, beautiful,
lots of Indian origin people there.
Great food, great culture, reasonably
good weather, great beaches. Uh, lots of
Eastern African nations are beautiful.
South Africa, despite whatever problems
there is, it's very nice. In Southeast
Asia, Indonesia is beautiful, wonderful
place. Uh, Singapore is great. Thailand,
Cambodia,
uh, Cambodia despite its recent horrible
history and tragic history. Vietnam is
fantastic. Uh Mongolia is a beautiful
country very very different climate from
what of us what all of us are used to
unless you have been to Ladak. Um
Mongolia's climate is better than Ladak.
Ladak it's very high altitudes because
because of that lot of people struggle
but uh otherwise the climate of Mongolia
is very similar to Ladak temperature
wise and all that. So Mongolia is full
of stunning natural beauty, fantastic
people, very meat heavy food and all but
still if you eat meat good for you and
so on. So I could Russia is beautiful.
Russia is fantastic. Lots of natural
beauty there. Tremendous natural beauty.
I would say great people, good food as
well.
And uh even I mean you could go on.
Argentina is wonderful. Beautiful.
Brazil is wonderful. Mexico is
wonderful. So you know what? I could go
do a world tour. I think I think
everyone's wonderful. Most most
countries are fantastic, wonderful,
beautiful. Um, you you can enjoy
yourself in any country and and have a
great experience in any country. Depends
on your attitude. And every country has
something to offer. Lots of Balkan
countries are fantastic. Croatia,
um, Serbia,
and so much more. So much more. Well,
I'm sure I've missed a few.
uh North African countries
have lot of beauty beauty and so on. I
New Zealand is beautiful. Australia is
beautiful. Come on. Right. So I I could
I could go on but I think I'll stop
there.
Okay, that brings me to the end of the
questions I have selected. Now I can see
that there's a super chat that I've not
taken. So I'll take that. It's by Aman
Siddings who says in Mediterranean Ryena
dialogue an am minister
on the same stage with with Dr. Junker
was talking about connectivity with the
EU just how is it landlocked? What's am
Armenia?
Are you talking about Armenia?
Uh connectivity with the EU. Armenia is
landlocked. Okay, let's take a look at
the map.
We'll take a look at the map and figure
out if you're talking about Armenia. It
it helps if you put the name proper name
of the country instead of an
abbreviation. But um maybe there's a
reason for it. Okay. So here's the map.
If you're talking about Armenia,
Armenia is landlocked. Yes. But they can
certainly access the EU from, for
example, Georgia. Uh Turka will never
allow Armenia because they hate Armenia.
They want Armenia to stop existing. But
Armenia can certainly u access the EU
via Georgia across the Black Sea into
the the European countries or maybe
through Georgia and Russia but then with
Ukraine in the way. Obviously Ukraine is
a war zone. So probably it's via Georgia
and the Black Sea. Beyond that, Armenia
is obviously landlocked and I'm not
aware of the context in which the
Armenian minister, if you're talking
about Armenia, was was speaking. So I I
don't really know.
uh if you give me more context maybe I
can give you a better answer but yeah
the that's what I can say right now
Armenia is indeed landlocked
as as is Mongolia for example but even
Mongolia can theoretically have
connectivity with the European Union via
land via something else perhaps
uh you can also have connectivity by air
but for for if if you're talking about
Armenia it could be through Georgia
through the through the uh Caspian sea
and then go into through through the
Black Sea, sorry, via Georgia, then the
Black Sea westwards and then across the
Black Sea you have Europe on the other
side. Uh so maybe that's what he was
referring to. Okay. U so let's maybe
take maybe two or three questions from
the live live chat. What do we have? Do
we have something? Um
uh so says love from Leal Nepal. Well,
love from India. We love all our Nepali
brothers and sisters. Uh, so we don't
endorse only. He's got a popularity of
20%. Okay. Well, thank you for letting
us know. I appreciate that.
Um, what else?
What do we have? Um, ML says, "Is there
a possibility that the US and China are
using Ukraine to drain Russia?" You US,
yes. West, yes. West, yes. China, no.
China wants Russia to remain the way it
is right now and to drain and and to
drain the west's west's resources via
Ukraine. Okay. Uh both US and China gain
more territory to extract and get rid of
the competition weaken um no the west
does want to use Ukraine to weaken
Russia for sure but a weakened Russia
further weakened Russia is not good for
China. So that's not the case. But
please remember that China is no friend
of Russia. If you watch my geio strategy
show, you will know exactly what I mean
by that. Uh Mr. Sharma is well, thank
you so much, sir. Appreciate that very
much. Thank you.
Okay. Now,
um I don't know anything about Vasu
astrology, so I won't take that. Okay.
Um
Okay. Do we have anything else? Um, Tmai
says, "What has made Donald Trump
suddenly become so reckless? Everything
said about him during the 2016 2020 term
is turning out to be true this term. Is
it that it will be his last term?" See,
US presidents have two terms only. So,
this is obviously his last term. Uh,
what's happened? What's happened is like
I have said he has kissed the ring,
which means that he's now an agent of
the deep state. If it does exist,
probably it does. And he is essentially
furthering their agenda. Their agenda
seems to be to shake up the entire world
and to launch an launch an economic war
in the entire world to to essentially
fragment the world economy.
Until now, until until the Biden
administration, the whole world was
interconnected in in a lot of sense in a
in a in in
so many ways, supply chains, economic
integration, so much more. But now and
and you know the US had very had a very
uh benevolent view of its allies and uh
NATO required did did not require each
NATO member to pay up to 5% of their GDP
for the upkeep of NATO which is why the
European nations were so prosperous. Now
that's going to not happen.
Uh and tariffs on all nations. So every
nation needs to pay the pay a tribute to
the US essentially. It's like the old
days of Roman taxation where all the
vasals had to pay tribute
or tax whatever you want to call it to
the overlord. So that's the kind of
thing that's happening and the Americans
are trying to bully India also open up
your market and let us dump our dump our
agricultural garbage into your country
which is not going to happen unless we
become a vasal. Um yeah
uh
two idiot NRA says rolls roy safh al-51
transfer of technology while read Russia
needs money or just deep on nextg kaviri
how does India not come in as late as
sixth generation etc look like I've said
this like maybe 500 times we need to
continue developing our own jet engine
indigenously at the same time we need to
either buy beg borrow for steal jet
engine technology from whoever is
willing to give it whoever whether it is
the French or the Russians or whoever
also it's not going to happen it's
western saf possible I'm sure they'll
ask for a lot of money if we can we
should pay it or maybe the Russian jet
engine just get your hands on one piece
of technology and acquire the full
technology toot transfer of technology
at the same time keep on developing your
jet engine even if it takes 30 years it
needs to happen in parallel and once we
have
bought let's say acquired technology
then we can transfer that into our jet
our own jet engine as well. Uh so that's
what needs to happen. The problem is
that you know we have woken up very
late. Uh this is something we should
have been doing since the 1940s 1950s
developing our own jet engines. It takes
time. It takes decades, multiple
decades. And the technology improves
iteratively slowly over time. But we we
are doing it now. So you know we are
behind. Even the Chinese have struggled
when it comes to jet engine technology.
Even they have struggled. But they seem
to have now kind of um they seem to be
on the right track now.
Okay.
Uh Bilawal Bhau has agreed to give Masar
to India. He has not agreed. Words. Do
you know the difference between words
and actions? Come on. Don't you know
that
it has nothing to do with operation
zindur? It's just talk. They will never
give mas masuda or any terrorist to
India.
Okay, that is the end of today's live
stream. Thank you so much everybody for
your questions. It was fun. U going
forward I will mostly take questions
from the comments only. That is the only
way to ensure that the quality of this
show remains at high standards.
Very often I found that if I take
questions only from the live chat, I get
sometimes not very good questions. Even
if I do super chats, sometimes I get
good questions, sometimes I don't get
great questions. So maybe I'll do the
super chats maybe once a month or so.
Mostly I will take questions from the
comments. That's the only way. The most
important thing over here is quality. I
can't allow the quality of the show to
degrade. Okay? Okay, I have to take the
best possible questions. So, uh, thank
you so much everybody for the questions
and I will see you in the live streams
that will that I'll do next week. Thank
you so much. Keep asking questions, keep
raising your standards, keep learning
and take care. I'll see you soon.
Bye-bye.